ANDREY SAFONOV

Vancouver, BC (Open to EST work hours) - safonand@gmail.com - (778) 922-3772 - linkedin.com/in/andrevsaf/

I started my career as a software engineer, developing text collaboration software. Later, I worked as an implementation consultant for the Ministry of Finance, where I built an online tax portal serving 5 million taxpayers. At my current company, I was the first PM, scaled the product from \$5M to \$50M, built a product management team and led the product through 2 private equity exits.

Experience

Director of Product

Apryse (PDFTron)

October 2021 - Present (1 year, 9 months)

- Established product function and currently leading a team of 5 PMs, 2 Designers, and 1 Product Marketing Manager
- Responsible for a \$50M portfolio consisting of Document SDKs, APIs and UI components used by 90% of Fortune 500
- Rolled out consumption-based pricing instead of value-based pricing and increased win rate from 30% to 85%
- Performed product integration planning and technical due diligence for M&A inorganic growth of 8 acquisitions
- Built an embeddable web DOCX editor generating \$3M in pipeline upon launch

Technical Product Manager

Apryse (PDFTron)

November 2019 - October 2021 (2 years)

- Unlocked a new distribution channel through Low-Code platform providers that brought \$5M ARR over the 2 years
- Created and delivered a roadmap that brought user value, business value and aligned with strategic direction
- Launched a new secure video review product that brought \$1M ARR in the first year
- Wrote technical documentation, developer guides, samples, blogs, and videos to improve product onboarding
- Crafted messaging for product launches, accompanying content, hosted webinars and sales enablement sessions

Technical Solutions Engineer

Apryse (PDFTron)

December 2018 - November 2019 (1 year)

- Helped Account Executives to close 25 deals amounting to \$3.5M TCV per guarter by building PoCs, running demos
- Worked closely with a team of developers to build out missing features for prospects
- Provided pre-sales and post-sales development support to customers

Implementation Consultant

Fast Enterprises

August 2015 - December 2018 (3 years 5 months)

Built an online portal for filing taxes for the Ministry of Finance in British Columbia that is used by 5M users today

Software Engineer

Mgestyk

September 2014 - August 2015 (1 year)

Worked on real-time collaborative text editor based on TinyMCE

Education

Bachelor of Applied Science - Computer Engineering

2011 - 2015 (4 years)

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)

December 2022

Skills

Product Strategy, Product Development, Product Marketing, Product Design, Solution Architecture, Pricing Strategy, People Development, Sales, Start-ups, API Development, Consulting, Developer Experience, Content Creation